Contact

majoargote@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/majoargote (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

French

Spanish

Excel

Languages

French (Native or Bilingual)
English (Native or Bilingual)
Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Lean Sensei

Series 65 - Uniform Investment Adviser

Mariajosé Argote

Founder & Operator | Purpose-driven | Exceptional Talent UK Visa Recipient

London, England, United Kingdom

Summary

I have 10 years of experience in growth, strategy and operations in demanding environments, an eye for identifying areas of opportunity and, most importantly, the dedication and scrappiness to capitalize on these. I have launched and scaled businesses in Brazil and Mexico, navigated regulated environments in the UK and the EU, and mentored startups in Colombia, the US, and Kenya. I've worked in the ever-changing landscapes of both new ventures and established companies, leaving a lasting impact on strategy, global expansion, and business growth.

I embrace challenges as chances to redefine what's possible.

Startup founders and senior corporate leaders have trusted me to take on and work through complex situations, turning confusion into clarity. People associate my name with reliability, and I'm skilled at finding paths to deliver on ambitious goals.

I'm proactive in my approach, entrepreneurial in my spirit, empathetic in my leadership, and resourceful in my execution. I have high expectations of myself and my contributions, and go above and beyond of what is expected. I find the positive in all situations and aim to learn something new every day.

Please feel free to connect with me or contact me at majoargote@gmail.com with any thoughts, comments, or questions about my work. I'm always interested in making new professional acquaintances.

Experience

POM Health Co-founder and CEO November 2023 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Page 1 of 6

London Area, United Kingdom

Self-Employed - Mentoring & Advising Startups Growth Strategy & Ops Advisor May 2020 - Present (5 years 2 months)

Working in a senior management and advisor capacity with a variety of startups in the US, Latin America and Europe. As a fractional executive, I leverage my international expansion, product launch, and general business management experience to help startups find product/market fit, fundraise, and scale. I have led and advised on fundraising lifecycle, managing pitch development, developing financial projections, and building an investor and advisor network, delivering pivotal support in refining business strategies, optimizing operations, and supporting strategic hires.

- Trusted advisor and fractional executive to 6+ startups spanning landscapes of US, Colombia, EU, and Kenya, extending guidance to including founders, CEOs, CTOs, and CFOs.
- Elevated narratives and crafted pitch materials for two startups, yielding transformative results, contributing to one startup's acceptance into prestigious California accelerator, while another secured substantial \$2M debt investment.
- Connected startups with plethora of advisors, freelancers, and investors within VC ecosystem, fostering 20+ constructive VC dialogues, welcoming new board advisors, and facilitating fruitful freelance contracts.

Companies include: Manifesto Markets, Humn, Floom, Valiu (YC19), Evolectric, to name a few.

I'm always open to meeting and chatting with new companies and teams.

SBI | Sales Benchmark Index Independent Management Consultant August 2021 - Present (3 years 11 months)

Antler
Entrepeneur
October 2023 - December 2023 (3 months)
London, England, United Kingdom

Humn
Head of Expansion & Corp Dev
February 2022 - November 2023 (1 year 10 months)
London, England, United Kingdom

Humn is a UK insurtech using data and ML to calculate, price and manage vehicle and road risk in real time.

I led the establishment and expansion of company's presence across EU market, including strategic direction, regulatory requirements, team recruitment, operational setup, and corporate partnerships. I also managed all budget, people, and operational aspects of international launches.

Most recently, my responsibilities have expanded beyond international. I coordinate with C-suite to devise and execute strategies for key priorities, fostering cohesion for streamlined initiatives. Moreover, I had a leading role in Humn's UK and international partnerships - driving initial conversations through execution.

- Enlisted by CEO to drive paramount commercial role within company's toptier strategic partnerships, cultivating robust alliances with industry giants such as QBE, Admiral, and Ford.
- Expanded Humn's insurance and risk management platform by managing stakeholders, creating new processes, and ultimately delivering a 3-year partnership with QBE UK (valued at £15M) which further strengthen Humn's position as an insurance and risk management leader in the UK taxi market.
- Achieved underwriting binding agreement valued at £15M in EU, cutting the typical arrangement timeline from 24 months to 12 months. This binding agreement unlocked Belgian regulatory approval and access to 27 EU markets.

Evolectric Advisor July 2021 - June 2022 (1 year)

Cargo Systems Inc.

1 year 11 months

Director, Corp Dev & Innovation
February 2020 - October 2020 (9 months)

Promoted to Director of Corp Dev & Innovation and served as right hand to CEO during company pivot. I supported with financial planning, facilitated internal realignment to company goals with clear initiatives, and nurtured strategic partnerships.

Sr. Manager International Operations & Expansion July 2019 - February 2020 (8 months)

Greater New York City Area

Cargo is a marketing and logistics platform for the rideshare industry. Cargo raised a Series A of \$20m led by Founders Fund in 2018 (total funding to date \$47m). In the summer of 2018 Cargo also signed a global exclusive partnership with Uber.

I owned and managed relationships and stakeholders across HQ, Brazil and Mexico, leading the prioritization and management of multiple projects, with limited resources (operational, tech and financial) in a fast and dynamic environment.

- Led the first international launch of Cargo, devising the entire launch from planning to hiring a team of 5 to building core operations, ultimately making Cargo Brazil the fastest market to reach 500 active users.
- Re-structured the business and operating model for international markets, securing buy-in from the CEO and making Brazil first market to margin positive from day 0, with a retail conversion that was 4x that of the US average.
- Worked closely with our CTO in redesigning our hardware; it allowed us to reduce costs from ~\$20 to ~\$5 per kit, install and ramp up faster, facilitating positive unit economics for our Brazil market.
- Growth-hacked our driver onboarding flow for Cargo Mexico, created plan of action, and collaborated with marketing, product, and operations to execute overhaul within week, within a few weeks our activation rate improved from 10% to 30%.

International Expansion Manager December 2018 - July 2019 (8 months) New York, New York, États-Unis

KPMG US

4 years 6 months

Senior Strategy Associate October 2016 - November 2018 (2 years 2 months)

Greater New York City Area

- Executed comprehensive quantitative and qualitative research and analysis
 to support M&A and growth strategy initiatives whilst synthesizing outcomes,
 insights, and strategic directives into presentations both management and
 clients.
- Co-developed business strategy and three-year implementation roadmap for the sales arm of a national retailer
- Performed market size, trends, and competitive landscape analysis on healthtech Israeli company on behalf of a large US private equity fund; ultimately, findings and report enabled a \$500M investment into the company
- Managed junior team members during a customer strategy development project; developed and conducted online, mobile and in-person surveys, and presented findings and recommendations to the CEO and Chief of Staff of a \$4.5 billion retailer

Strategy Associate

June 2014 - October 2016 (2 years 5 months)

New York City Metropolitan Area

- Co-developed the framework and playbook for entry into direct-to-consumer channels in the consumer and retail space based on industry trends; presented the go-to-market implementation plan to the executive team of a Fortune 500 company.
- Conducted the due diligence of a high profile IT software merger, with a concentration on quantifying revenue synergies and growth prospects for the combined entity.
- Advised executive leadership at a global utilities firm, driving performance improvements by analyzing SG&A cost reductions and enhancing service quality between headquarters and regional divisions.

Nielsen

Marketing Analytics Consulting Intern - Price & Promotion Strategy June 2013 - August 2013 (3 months)

Greater Chicago Area

- Researched and authored a comprehensive analytical presentation for a Fortune 500 client supporting Nielsen's promotion effectiveness (PSOV) study methodology through the use of Nielsen data and managerial economics
- Enhanced client-consultant relationship for over sixty project managers and analysts by developing and presenting a business process improvement training, with tutorials and user guides, enabling faster access to descriptive CPG data

BBVA

Economic Research Intern July 2012 - August 2012 (2 months) Bogota, Colombia

- Compiled and analyzed key economic drivers behind Colombia's socioeconomic and financial progress, which was presented in a 40 page report to executive management, forecasting financial investment in the Colombian economy
- Delivered daily economic indicators via Bloomberg to over 400 analysts, treasurers, and clients, conveying both Colombian and international financial figures needed to support daily loans, risk analyses and currency exchange operations
- Translated BBVA Economic Global Research slide decks to and from Spanish, resulting in clearer, faster and more accurate deliverables for the economic research, treasury and stock exchange departments

Education

Indiana University - Kelley School of Business
Bachelors of Science, Business Economics, Public Policy Analysis &
International Business; French Minor · (2010 - 2014)

Hamilton Southeastern High School (2006 - 2010)